So we have our yummy bacon, I'm taking it to our cast iron grill which is kind of smoking right now, which is the way I want it.
This really brings me home because it's cast iron, it's grandma's, it's a variation on a traditional dish that I grew up with.
I want to turn my flame down to about a medium flame, you don't want the bacon to burn.
"You don't want the pork fat to burn" as my grandmother would say.
If this was my grandmother she wouldn't be using bacon she would be using lard and fat back which is something that I use sometimes but bacon seems to be a lot more convenient.
It's got the nice smoky flavor.
My grandmother had a farm in Wisconsin.
When ever she got bacon, it was from the pig, smoked there, no preservatives, no bad stuff in it.
All the meat was definitely big, it was half the size of a cow.
I grew up really having a wonderful experience with food.
She had her own big garden, chickens running around, it was amazing.
It starting me on my culinary journey.
looking at this job takes me right back to it.
As you can see our bacon is starting to crisp up nicely, it's going to give a lot of nice flavor to our meat.